Guide to the Doris Duke Audiovisual Collection, 1919-2012 and undated RL.10005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Moving Images, 1899-2012 and undated
  - Film, 1919-2012; 220 items
    - W. Choi Shangri La, circa early 1940s (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0001, Video-file RL10005-F8-0001_uc.mp4)
      - Original 8mm reversal print, 40 film feet (Box 2, Film-reel RL10005-F8-0001)
    - Of Men and Money, circa 1944
      Documentary film based on the book "Defense of Capitalism" by James Cromwell and Hugo Czerwonky. Doris Duke was married to James Cromwell. Appears that this may be a rough cut of the film.
      - Original 16mm, sd., bw reversal print, 250 film feet (Box 2, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0032)
    - The Nazi Supreme Court Trial of the Anti-Hitler Plot September 1944-January 1945, 1944-1945 (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0003, Video-file RL10005-F35-0001_uc.mp4 - RL10005-F35-0004_uc.mp4)
      - Original 35mm Negative, 1100 film feet (Film-reel 1, Film-reel RL10005-F35-0001)
        Footage covering the show trial of members of the failed Hitler assassination attempt held September 1944 and January 1945. Includes examination of Chaplain Wehrte, von Leonard's confessor, Dr. Josef Wirmer, Dr. Brüning's former secretary, Von Hassel, former Ambassador to Italy. Prepared and presented by Office of Strategic Services Field Photographic Branch. Film is in German.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 35mm Negative, 1100 film feet (Film-reel 2, Film-reel RL10005-F35-0002)
        Footage covering the show trial of members of the failed Hitler assassination attempt held September 1944 and January 1945. Includes shots of a report titled "Attentat auf den Führer am 20. Juli 1944" or "Assination attempt of the Führer on July 20, 1944" which shows pictures of the room where the assination attempt took place. Also includes examination of Lt. Gen. von Haase, Army Commandant of Berlin, Count York von Wartenburg, Major on Stauffenberg's Staff, Count Schwerin von Schwanenfeld, and Dr. Goerdeler, "the political leader of the plot". Prepared and presented by Office of Strategic Services Field Photographic Branch. Film is in German.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 35mm Negative, 1100 film feet (Film-reel 3, Film-reel RL10005-F35-0003)
        Footage covering the show trial of members of the failed Hitler assassination attempt held September 1944 and January 1945. Includes examination of Count von Helldorf, Berlin Chief of Police, Trott zu Solz, Counselor of Legation in the Foreign Office. Prepared and presented by Office of Strategic Services Field Photographic Branch. Film is in German.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 35mm Negative, 1100 film feet (Film-reel 4, Film-reel RL10005-F35-0004)
        Footage covering the show trial of members of the failed Hitler assassination attempt held September 1944 and January 1945. Begins with a brief overview in English about the trial. Includes examination of General Field Marshal von Witzleben, former Army Commander on the Western Front, and Col. Gen. Hoeppner, former Commander of a Panzer Army in the East. Prepared and presented by Office of Strategic Services Field Photographic Branch. Film is in German.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
    - Seminoles of the Everglades, Print #226, Part A&B, 1949
      Describes the Seminole Indians of Florida and the great swamp area by which they live. Produced by Shilin Film Service Corporation.
      - Original 16mm, sd., col. reversal print, 800 film feet (Box 3, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0017)
    - Miracle on the Mesa, Print #1, A&B, 1950
      Records the way of life of the Hopi Indians which has persisted in a traditional pattern for seven centuries. Points out the need of the Hopi people for water conservation program, and show extant Hopi villages in the Arizon desert. Produced by Shilin Film Service Corporation.
      - Original 16mm, sd., col. reversal print, 800 film feet (Box 4, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0018)
    - DD 4, 5, 6, circa mid 1950s (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0002, Video-file RL10005-F16-0014_uc.mp4)
      Footage shot primarily at Duke Farms. Includes Doris Duke, Joey Castro and unidentified children and teenagers in MG convertible, dogs, etc. Views of Duke Farms from moving car, blurry views of Hay Barn, Gardens, and winter scenes. Shots of construction on Duke Farms Estate, Doris and Joey Castro admiring statues. Front patio of Residence; a little girl dances, then Joe Castro and unidentified woman dance. Also inlcudes picnic with Doris Duke and unknown people and close up shots of art work inside the main residence. Short clip of New York City skyline.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 16mm, si., col., bw reversal print, 1200 film feet (Box 3, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0014)
    - DD 22, 23, 25-33, circa 1950s-1960s (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0002, Video-file RL10005-F16-0009_uc.mp4)
      Includes Doris Duke in blue bikini swimsuit and cast on wrist sitting and standing by rail at Shangri La. View of interior patio, with unidentified man inspecting tile. Doris Duke in dress walks around Shangri La, dogs follow. She puts blossom in hair. Unidentified man in red swim trunks stands on diving board as it raises up. View of Golden Temple in Bangkok, Thailand. Also includes beach and hill scenery, close up shots of unknown man driving around the island, sunsets, view from inside an airplane/aerial views of island, and close up views of mihrab in Shangri La.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 16mm, si., col. reversal print, 700 film feet (Box 1, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0009)
    - DD 44, circa 1950s-1960s (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0001, Video-file RL10005-F16-0006_uc.mp4)
      Features trip to India, Bombay and the Taj Mahal. Views of landscapes, people walking around near Taj Mahal; includes some brief views of Doris Duke.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 16mm, si., col. reversal print, 800 film feet (Box 3, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0006)
    - Ladd Interiors: Bedouin, circa 1951 (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0003, Video-file RL10005-F16-0037_uc.mp4)
      Custom original print of women Lebanese dancers (accompanied by musicians) sent to Doris Duke at her apartment at 475 Park Avenue in New York. Also marked as "Dance film; Bob Farrah".Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 16mm, sd., col. reversal print, 600 film feet (Box 10, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0037)
    - Ladd Interiors - Bedouin, circa 1951
      - Original 16mm, opt track Soundtrack, 550 film feet (Box 10, Film-reel RL10005-F16OS-0001)
    - Ladd Interiors - Nadia Gamal, circa 1951
      - Original 16mm, opt track Soundtrack, 900 film feet (Box 3, Film-reel RL10005-F16OS-0002)
    - Fallen Eagle, Print #5, Part A&B, 1952
      An account of the Sioux Indians of the South Dakota plains, with an informative record of their past culture and an eye-opening picture of their past existence. Produced by Shilin Film Service Corporation.
      - Original 16mm, sd., col. reversal print, 800 film feet (Box 2, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0016)
    - DD 21, 1955 (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0001, Video-file RL10005-F16-0004_uc.mp4)
      Primarily shots of Shangri La. Shows Shangri La patio with unidentified people at the beginning. Joe Castro and unknown man on diving board as it rises; various shots Doris Duke with others on sailing boat. Also includes some brief shots of Duke Farms, including Doris looking at Old Foundation with Joe Castro, Louis Bromfield[?], and others.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 16mm, si., col. reversal print, 400 film feet (Box 5, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0004)
    - [Untitled], circa 1956
      Film includes Mrs. Castro[?] (Joey Castro's mother) on the Empire State Building, views of New York City, aerial views from an airplane (New York or New Jersey?)
      - Original 16mm, si., col. reversal print, 35 film feet (Box 4, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0038)
    - Syd Shaw Films, circa 1958
      All reels are 16mm, si., col. reversal prints unless otherwise noted.
      - Syd Shaw, East West Films, circa 1958; 1000 film feet (Box 4, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0021)
        Primarily shots of young girl/children underwater. Other shots of water/islands presumably in Tahiti.
      - Syd Shaw, East West Films, New Sounds, Reel 2, 3, circa 1960s; 1000 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0042)
        Includes Rolls 3A and 4A. Roll 3A has various short scenes including the ocean scenes, shots of the island(s), man fishing with spear, children swimming, dogs playing on beach, and women with child washing clothes. Roll 4A includes scenes of man and woman on boat, palm trees, sunset on beach, various flowers/lillies, and women with flowers in their hair.
      - Syd Shaw, East West Films, New Sounds, Reel 6, Animals&Kids, circa 1960s; 900 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0044)
        Includes Rolls A and 16A. Roll A has young male dancers in white native dress performing with musicians in outdoor setting. Includes long shots and close-ups of performers. Roll 16A has same male dancers performating at different venue, joined by female dancers. Also includes different set of dancers in different dress, close-ups of children and women washing clothes in pond.
      - East West New Sounds, Reel 2, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 1000 film feet (Box 3, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0045)
        Various scenes including water, palms trees, fauna, Tahitian musicians and dancers performing in front of outdoor audience, shots of angles, and underwater scenes. 16mm, si., col., negative.
      - Syd Shaw East West New Sounds Reel I, circa 1960s; 1000 film feet (Box 3, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0047)
        Includes Rolls 1D, 3D, 4D, 5D, 6A, and 6D. Majority of the film iare underwater scenes and include shots of water, coral reef, fish, and children swimming under water.
      - [Syd Shaw], circa 1960s; 550 film feet (Box 5, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0048)
        Roll 16A. Identical footage as Roll 16A in RL10005-F16-0044.
      - Flower, waterfall, "very good", Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 350 film feet (Box 5, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0049)
        Various shots of palm trees, sunset, water, and man canoeing in sunset. Marker indicates this film is Roll 13A.
      - Water lillies, palm trees, gold fish, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 400 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0050)
        Close ups of flower, palm trees, water lillies, goldfish, and water fall. Markers indicate this film includes Roll 1A and 17A. Handwritten note on original container "DD likes this one".
      - Syd Shaw 'Children and Dogs', Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 200 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0051)
        Various close-ups of unknown Tahitian children. Sometimes children are with dogs.
      - Boat Parade, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 200 film feet (Box 5, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0052)
        Various shots of boats colorfully decorated with flowers. Includes some shots of the sky.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 300 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0053)
        Various shots of Tahitian musicians and others greeting visitors with leis. Close ups of unknown Tahitian men and women, instruments. Long shots of islands, water, and small sailing boat with unknown people. Markers indicate this film includes Rolls 2A and 10A.
      - Women in pond, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 150 film feet (Box 37, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0054)
        Shots of various unknown Tahitian women swimming in pond, walking around in fauna.
      - Syd Shaw Rolls 3-4-12 Outtakes, circa 1960s; 850 film feet (Box 7, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0058)
        See description for Rolls 3A and 4A. Roll 12A includes various shots of native children, reflections of palm trees on beach, palm trees, fauna, and dogs.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 500 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0061)
        "Dancing", "Dance" written on film leader tape. Includes native dancers at outdoor event.
      - Syd Shaw 'Scenery' Misc, circa 1960s; 375 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0062)
        Includes Rolls 2A, 4A, and 6A. Contains assorted clips of island, sunsets, birds, palm trees, sailing, fishing, children, etc.
      - People at Fete', 'Boat crowd', Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 325 film feet (Box 7, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0063)
        Includes long shots and close-ups of various native men, women, and children at different events and locations.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 600 film feet (Box 7, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0064)
        Male dancers at outdoor event; women dancers performing. Includes close-ups of dancers.
      - Trims, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 400 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0065)
        Includes aerial shots of islands, water, waterfalls, and brief underwater scences. Heavily spliced so scenes are relatively short.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 300 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0066)
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 300 film feet (Box 9, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0067)
        Either Roll 1 or 9. All aerial shots of island.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 375 film feet (Box 5, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0068)
        Native dancers at outdoor event. Includes long shots and close-up shots.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 400 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0069)
        Includes shots of island, water, boat parade with spectators, and close-ups of flowers.
      - Fete Dancing Groups, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 250 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0070)
        Native dancers at outdoor event.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 200 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0071)
        Roll A. Male dancers in white native dress performing with musicians in outdoor setting. Includes long shots and close-ups of performers.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 250 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0072)
        Includes various shots of fauna, water, island, people in canoes, people walking on beach.
      - Scenery, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 200 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0073)
        Includes parts from Roll 15A. Also has "Jungle", "Rain on leaves" written directly on film. Primarily all scenery including water at sunset, palm trees, and island.
      - Scenery, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 225 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0074)
        Various scenes on the island. "Flower Trim" is written on the film
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 250 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0075)
        Various shots of island, native people and boat parade.
      - Dancers in Grove, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 200 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0076)
        Native men and women in white costumes dancing. Includes long shots and close-ups.
      - Aerial-Water, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 300 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0077)
        Aerial shots of island, water.
      - Ladies-Fish-Underwater, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 200 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0078)
        Variety of scenes.
      - Scenery-Aerial, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 275 film feet (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0079)
        Includes parts from Roll 13A. Various shots of flowers, sunsets.
      - Underwater-Misc, Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 200 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0080)
        Includes parts from Roll 5D.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 150 film feet (Box 9, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0081)
        Includes Roll 12A.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 150 film feet (Box 9, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0082)
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 150 film feet (Box 9, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0083)
        Includes Roll 14A.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s; 150 film feet (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0084)
        Includes Roll 4A.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0085 through RL10005-F16-0089 (5 films total))
        Consists of small reels less than 100'. Presumably rough cuts of various scenes in Tahiti.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s (Box 8, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0090 through RL10005-F16-0096 (7 films total))
        Consists of small reels less than 100'. Premably rough cuts of various scenes in Tahiti.
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s (Box 10, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0097 through RL10005-F16-0104 (8 films total))
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0105 through RL10005-F16-0115 (10 films total))
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s (Box 9, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0116 through RL10005-F16-0120 (5 films total))
      - [Untitled], Syd Shaw Productions, circa 1960s (Box 6, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0121 through RL10005-F16-0123 (3 films total))
      - Syd Shaw, East West Films, New Sounds, Reel 7, 1968 Jun 17; 1200 film feet (Box 4, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0046)
        Includes Rolls 1A, 2A, and 13A. Roll 1A has various sunset shots, shots of the island(s), water, leaves, trees, and flowers. Roll 2A includes man in canoe, woman walking on beach, and shots of various unknown native men and women. Roll 13A is all close-up shots of native men, women, and children.
      - East West New Sounds, Reel #5, Syd Shaw Productions, 1968 May 18; 1000 film feet (Box 4, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0041)
        Includes Rolls 15A and 18A. Roll 15A has shots of various native dancers and musicians performing at different outdoor venues. The roll also includes shots of the island, palm trees, water, and close-ups of pigs feeding. Roll 18A includes shots of the sky, a boat parade and three women performing a dance.
      - Syd Shaw, East West Films, New Sounds, Reel 4, 1968 May 28; 1100 film feet (Box 7, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0043)
        Includes Rolls 10A and 14A. Roll 10A has various shots of island(s), ocean, various people on boats, close-up of mother with child, and groups of unknown people. Roll 14A starts with close-up of child's hand, various boats, groups of non-native people preparing for sailing, water falls, and palm trees.
      - Outtakes Reel 6, Syd Shaw Productions, 1968 May 28; 800 film feet (Box 7, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0059)
        See description for Reel 6.
      - S. Shaw Rolls 10A-14A-11 Outtakes, 1968 May 28; 800 film feet (Box 4, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0060)
        See descriptions for Rolls 10A and 14A. Roll 11 includes women by water, with one woman playing guitar and one presumably singing.
    - DD45, circa 1960s (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0003, Video-file RL10005-F16-0057_uc.mp4)
      Opening views of Doris Duke walking through Golden Pavillion area of Bangkok. Beginning is good evidence since it references SEAAC. Also includes Doris, Joey Castro, and unknown man visiting other locations in Bangkok and Thailand.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 16mm, si., col. reversal print, 1400 film feet (Box 7, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0057)
    - Khaled Original, 1971 (Digital-materials RL10005-SET-0003, Video-file RL10005-F16-0019_uc.mp4)
      Film features Nadia Gamal, who is considered to be a queen of belly dancers. Original filming commissioned by Ibrahim Farrah with the support of a grant from Doris Duke. Consists of three different solos, directed by Mounir Maasri. Music by Rafik Hobeika, Sacalance, and Baligh Hamdi.Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - Original 16mm, sd., col. reversal print, 1100 film feet (Box 4, Film-reel RL10005-F16-0019)
  - Video, 1989-2012; 11 items
    This subseries consists primarily of VHS tapes that were likely given to Doris Duke as a gift or sent to her as a means to solicit financial support. Of particular interest are the tapes of Duke Gardens which were made for the benefit of Doris Duke. The unknown narrator explains to Miss Duke what plants are in the gardens and points out changes that had been made to the various gardens.
    - Wayne Skjoldal, 1989 May (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0017)
      Wayne Skjoldal
    - 1990 American Dance Honors (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0018)
      1990 American Dance Honors
    - Duke Gardens Xmas 1990, 1990 December 25 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0020)
      Duke Gardens Xmas 1990
    - Duke Gardens 3-21-92, 1992 March 21 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0021)
      Duke Gardens 3-21-92
    - A Jewel in the Queen's Crown, undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0011)
      A Jewel in the Queen's Crown
    - Self Realization Fellowship: Security in a World of Change, an informal talk by Sri Daya Mata, undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0013)
      Self Realization Fellowship: Security in a World of Change, an informal talk by Sri Daya Mata
    - Thirteen Daughters, Act I, undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0014)
      Thirteen Daughters, Act I
    - Thirteen Daughters, Act II, undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0015)
      Thirteen Daughters, Act II
    - Gardens Great and Small, undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0016)
      Gardens Great and Small
    - A Personal Invitation to Doris Duke from Mayor Sharpe James, undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL-10005-VHS-0019)
      A Personal Invitation to Doris Duke from Mayor Sharpe James
    - At Home with Doris Duke: Selections from her Personal Home Movies, 2012 Jan 7; 24 minutes (Box 11, Video-disc RL10005-DVD-0008)
      At Home with Doris Duke: Selections from her Personal Home Movies
- Audio, 1923-1989
  The Audio series reflects Doris Duke's interest in a variety of music genres and is arranged into three subseries by format. Materials include phonodiscs, open-reel audio tapes, and audiocassettes.
  Digital copies of audio materials are indicated by a Digital Materials designation. While many of the audio resources in the Doris Duke Audiovisual collection have been digitized, those that have not require digitization prior to access. Please contact Rubenstein Library Research Services for further information.
  - Phonodiscs, 1934-1989; 198 items
    Many of the recordings in this subseries are homemade and date from the 1930s-1940s. Besides collecting the commercial recordings of well-known jazz, gospel, and classical artists, Doris was also very interested in Hawaiian music and recorded many of these native songs live using recordings equipment likely kept at her Shangri La estate. She also recorded herself and friends practicing the piano and singing, parties, and recorded and collected radio broadcasts including the broadcast of KGU Radio Artists "The Story of James Buchanan Duke" from 1949. Also included in this subseries are original recordings of the Joe Castro Trio, Kitty White, and Calvin Jackson practicing with his quartet. Of particular interest are the original recordings of the Kahanamoku family and Sol Ho'opi'I who recorded Hawaiian songs for Doris when she wasn't "in residence" at Shangri La.
    - Dorothy Holt. Special Piano Solo., 1934 July 18
      - Original lacquer phonodisc (Box 15, Audio-phonodisc RL10005-PD-0028)
    - Fats Waller Favorites - Victor Musical Smart Set - "Honeysuckle Rose"/ "Your Feet's Too Big", 1937
      - Phonodisc (Box 20, Audio-phonodisc RL10005-PD-0128)
    - Fats Waller Favorites - Victor Musical Smart Set - "Ain't Misbehavin'" / "Hold Tight", 1937
      - Phonodisc (Box 20, Audio-phonodisc RL10005-PD-0129)